so hi my name is Joe brewer and I'm a
change strategist the thing that I want
to talk to you about today is what every
culture designer absolutely needs to
know which is the way that ignorance
arises in a society and I'm going to
review this book agne Tala G the making
and unmaking of ignorance edited by
Robert Procter & linda Schwab anger and
this is a book about a new field of
scholarship agnate ology which is the
study of how ignorant arises in
societies and the reason this is
extremely important is because ignorance
is something that can create it be
created as a form of knowledge so let me
give you an example back in the early
days of cancer research it was
discovered that there was a link between
smoking and lung cancer and so then the
tobacco industry started to set up fake
research firms to intentionally spread
misinformation about the science so what
they did was they took a type of
knowledge that was factually incorrect
and spreaded in society so that it's
stuck in people's minds making them
ignorant of the real knowledge of the
science what the science was actually
saying so this process of designing and
creating ignorance is something that is
very very important for us to understand
as changemakers so more recently there's
also been the the work over the last few
decades where billions of dollars have
been spent by oil companies to confuse
people and miss inform them about the
threats and the findings of climate
science in the same way this is a way of
creating ignorance because the knowledge
that gets spread which is valued
judgments beliefs assumptions assertions
about what the science does or does not
say that actually gets in the way of
people knowing what is actually going on
so one of our challenges as culture
designers is to take this understanding
of AG matala G or the scholarly work
studying how ignorance is created in
society and then applying that knowledge
to help the ideas that are needed for
society to thrive and to have resilience
for those ideas to spread so one of the
other things that I really liked in this
book in particular was the way that it
described how different
ways of creating ignorance have been
used as kind of case studies throughout
history so yes it goes through the
philip morris story of lung cancer and
its connection to smoking and also the
disinformation and misinformation around
climate science but it also looks at
more subtle issues that are equally
important for making the transition to
sustainability such as the way that we
view and comprehend human sexuality and
gender differences between men and women
so one of the ways that ignorance was
pervasive throughout most of medical
history was in the confusion and I would
say the attention being directed away
from understanding female sexuality
which turns out to be very important for
maintaining systems of dominance and
oppression against women and patriarchal
systems of power so the the way that
ignorance was maintained about female
sexuality in the female body was part of
a larger system of oppression that kept
patriarchal masculine dominance with mom
types of worldviews and hierarchies in
place so this book explores the
mechanisms and methods by which this
ignorance is created how it's maintained
how its spread and I think it's an
extremely important resource for anyone
who wants to understand how to help the
ideas spread that humanity will need
which is exactly what culture design
focuses on doing so this is a great book
as a foundational text for anyone that
wants to understand how ignorance is
created as a body of knowledge and what
we can do about it so I hope you go out
and get this book and read it and then
ponder and apply the thinking to your
own work so that we can spread the ideas
the humanity needs to the right to
survive and thrive so that's it i canna
cognate ology by robert procter & linda
schwabing or as editors go and get a
copy and enjoy